陈述句语调与疑问句语调。你可能在某个时候学过，
Statement versus question intonation. You may have learned at some point that
问题会使用上升语调。确实如此，但通常问题会一级一级地上升，
questions have a rising intonation. They do, but usually a question will step
到最后，然后快速向下走一小步。
upward until the very end where it takes one quick little downward step. A question
疑问句会比同样语调模式的陈述句升得稍高一点。下面是
rises a little higher than a statement with the same intonation pattern. Here's
my car。Where's my car？情绪化或修辞性疑问句语调。如果你
my car. Where's my car? Emotional or rhetorical question intonation. If you
知道你的车停在外面，但有人没看到它，
know that your car is parked outside, however, and someone doesn't see it and
问你它在哪里，你可能会认为它被盗了，
ask you where it is, you might think that it has been stolen, and your emotion will
当你重复这个问题时，情绪上升会体现在语调里。
show in your intonation as you repeat the question. As your feelings rise in an
在情绪化场景中，你的语调会随着情绪一起升高：Where's my car？Why？
emotional situation, your intonation rises up along with them. Where's my car? Why?
车不见了吗？
Is it gone?